SAMUEL OLUWATOBI BABALOLA

10 Greenwood Street, New Britain, CT

(860) 938 1439 | sammytech.net@gmail.com | http://sammytech.me/ | https://github.com/sammytech

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Objective

A self-motivated programmer with 6+ years of programming, who is willing to learn. Seeking to leverage my experience to increase company's productivity. To gain additional experience in software development. To be part of a mission to develop software used by variety of people.

Core Competencies

Programming • Problem Solving • Relational Database • Mobile Development • Android Development iOS development • Software Development • Backend Development

Technical Competencies

<u>Applications</u>: Android Studio • XCode • Eclipse • IntelliJ • Microsoft Office • phpMyAdmin • Git

<u>Languages</u>: Java • Swift • Python • PHP • C • C++ • MIPS • HTML • CSS • MySQL • Node.js

Javascript • React-Native • Angular

Platforms: OSX • Windows • Linux • AWS

Professional Experience

Evolution Radio, Indianapolis, IN

06/2015 – 06/2016

(Software Developer Freelancer)

- Designed and created the application for both Android and iOS platforms.
- Reduced cost of developing the mobile application by recommending the usage of a MBaaS (Mobile Backend as a Service) platform Backendless.
- Created a web application to manage push notification in the mobile application.
- Communicated frequently with the client on the progress of the application.
- Successfully submitted mobile application to the apple and play store.
- Recommended technical solutions that helped the company determine the user interface of their website.

Vuse LLC, Rochester, NY

11/2014- 04/2016

(Software Developer)

Univent

04/2015 – 04/2016

A mobile application which gave students at college campuses the ability to be aware of events around them.

- Created the Android version of the mobile application
- Managed a team of 4 developers
- Created the RESTful API used by all the application
- Created a web scrapper to get information from specific websites
- Successfully submitted mobile application to the play store
- Delivered a weekly/bi-weekly update on the progress of the application.
- Designed and implemented the database

Vlipd

11/2014 - 03/2015

A mobile application which allowed users to record, share and collaborate with other users.

- Presented mobile application at Imagine RIT
- Developed the application for iOS
- Accelerated development by using a MBaaS (Mobile Backend as a Service) platform Parse.

Trafex 03/2017 - Present

A mobile application which allows students on a college campus to buy, sell, and exchange books among each other

- Using Parse Server (open source API server written in Node.js)
- Currently developing for android devices
- Using MongoDB

Education

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science

Graduating in December 2017, The College at Brockport, SUNY; Brockport, NY

Relevant Courses

Object Oriented Software Development

Created a library system, which allows a worker to add, and modify books', workers', and students' information. This system was built using Java and MySQL Web Application Development

Created an administrative dashboard, which allowed its users to add items, add promotions, add advertising events, and generated a report. This system was built using Php(Laravel), HTML5, MySQL, CSS (Bootstrap), and Javascript (JQuery).

Associate of Science, Computer Science

Graduated in May 2016, Monroe Community College; Rochester, NY

Relevant Courses

Programming Embedded Micro-controller in C and Assembly

Developed a motorized robot using a DragonBoard Micro-controller.

Concepts of Parallel and Distributed Systems

Developed a server-client desktop application in Java. This application allowed users to play a two player dice game over a network. The application pairs users up whenever there is another available player.